Timing and Subtitles by The Immortal Team @MKDORAMAS
동기화 및 자막 by The Immortal Team @mkdoramas
In one's life, there is a time when God stops by.
누구의 인생이건, 신이 머물다가는 순간이 있다.
The moments spent with you were all blindingly bright.
너와 함께한 시간 모두 눈부셨다.
Because the day was good, because the day was not good,
날이 좋아서, 날이 좋지 않아서
because the day was just right.
날이 적당해서
♬  I’ll recognize you   ♬
♫ 꼭 알아볼게 ♫
All the days were good.
모든 날이 좋았다
No matter how I think about it, I think you're really a goblin.
난 암만 생각해도 아저씨가 도깨비 맞는거 같거든요.
I love you.
♫ 니가 없는 곳에서도 ♫ 사랑해요
Goblin [All the days were good.]
♫ 수많은 해가 져도 잊지 않을게 ♫
[Goblin's house]
♬  See ya   ♬
♬   Never will some day   ♬
♬  Never will some day  ♬
[Secretary Kim who appeared in the Goblin's house]
♬  Never far away  ♬
You are happy these days because of the magic that Goblin brings, right?
요즘 도깨비가 부린 마법때문에 행복하시죠?
Viewer ratings, hot issue, and even an all-kill on the music charts.
시청률, 화제성, 심지어 음원차트 올킬까지
We have prepared this for all of you who have fallen deep for Goblin.
'도깨비앓이'에 빠진 여러분들을 위해 준비했습니다.
The Lonely and Shining Goblin Special, "All the days were good."
쓸쓸하고 찬란하신 도깨비 스페셜:  모든 날이 좋았다.
Hello, I am Secretary Kim.
안녕하세요 김비서입니다.
Are they loan sharks that you know?
아는 사체업자입니까?
You startled me.
아, 깜짝이야.
Let's go in my car. [Inside Goblin, the scene stealer Secretary Kim.]
제 차로 가시죠.
♬  Why do you make my heart waver? Growl, growl, growl. [Explosive excitement, explosive charm]
왜 내맘을 흔드는건데~♫ 으르렁 으르렁 으르렁대♫
[Korea's first secretary idol, Secretary Kim, Jo Woo Jin]
국내 최초 비서돌 김비서 조우진
Now, starting from now,
자, 그럼 지금부터
so that you will be able to enjoy the remaining story...
여러분께서 남은 이야기를 더욱 쉽고 재밌게 즐길 수 있도록
We will show you the tangled stories of the emerging characters in a very exciting way.
등장인물들의 얽히고 설킨 이야기들을 아주 흥미롭게 보여드리려고 합니다.
You will stay tuned, won't you?
채널고정 해주실거죠?
So, the drama that is making everyone in the world dazzled, TVN's Goblin...
자, 세상 모두를 눈부시게 있는 tvn 10주년 특별기획 '도깨비'.
The beginning and center of that would be the Goblin.
그 모든것의 시작과 중심은 바로 도깨비겠죠?
Everyone, how did the Goblin come to be?
여러분 과연 도깨비는 어떻게 탄생하게 됐을까요?
[Time to summon the Goblin]
도깨비를 소환할 시간
He was
그는
water, fire, wind, the light and the darkness.
물이고 불이고 바람이며 빛이자 어둠이다.
The people called him God. (Shin=God)
백성들은 그를 신이라 불렀다.
Covered in red blood, he slashed his enemies,
시뻘건 피를 뒤집어쓴 채, 적을 베고 나아가는
he was literally a god of war.
그는 문자 그대로의 무신이었다.
If a soul dwells in an object that has been touched by human hands or drenched in blood,
사람의 손때나 피가묻은 물건에 영혼이 깃들면
he becomes a goblin.
도깨비가 태어난다.
[Sword] ♬ When I close my eyes ♬
♫ 나의 두 눈을 감으면 ♫
I don't know from where I should start.
♫ 떠오르는 그 눈동자  ♫ 어디서부터 어떻게 시작을 해야할까
One child was born.
한 아이가 태어났어
An older brother who was old enough to be his father was the emperor. [The emperor who was extremely ill]
아버지뻘의 큰 형이 황제였지.
Now there is only Yeo that's left.
이제 여 하나 남았다.
Let Yeo marry your sister and protect him.
여와 자네 누이를 혼인시켜 여를 지켜다오.
I will receive your command.
명을 받들겠습니다.
The last will and testament of the emperor was an unexpected turn of event for Park Joong Hun who was trying to get hold of royal power. [Park Joong Hun who was after royal power was not happy about the marriage.]
전 황제의 유언은 왕권을 보다 탄탄하게 하려던 박중헌의 계획에 변수가 되었지.
General Kim! Hooray!
김신장군 만세!
Above the people is the king, and above the king is God. (Shin=God)
백성위의 왕, 왕위의 신
And they say that that God is Kim Shin.
그 신이 김신을 일컫는다 합니다.
Put down your sword along with your rage and concerns.
분노와 염려를 담아 검을 내린다.
Go as far as you can and as much as possible do not come back.
될 수 있는 한 멀리 가고, 할 수 있는 한 돌아오지 말라.
It is Your Majesty's Goryeo.
폐하의 고려이옵니다.
I protected the borders because you told me to.
변방을 수비하라 명하시어 변방을 시켰고
I killed the enemies when you told me to.
적을 멸하라 명하시어 적을 멸하였고
My sister is here and my people--
누이가 여기에 있고 백성이 여기에 있는데
My concerns... it seems you are worrying about them for me. It's an order.
황제의 근심을 이젠 그대가 하는구나. 어명이다.
[Kim Shin is accused of being a traitor because the king fell for Park Joong Hun's plot.]
박중헌의 계략에 넘어가 역적으로 몰린 김신
The traitor Kim Shin is to put his sword down and kneel down to accept the king's command.
대역죄인 김신은 검을 물고 무릎을 꿇고 어명을 받들라.
What do you mean traitor? Are you crazy?
대역죄인이라니 미쳤느냐?
Have you gone out of your mind?
돌았느냐?!
It's treason! Don't let anyone in that household live!
역모다! 저 집안의 그 누구의 숨도 붙여두지 말라.
It's an order!
어명이다!
[King Yeo kills his queen and Kim Shin, having fallen for the trickery of a treacherous servant.]
간신의 농간에 빠져 황후와 김신을 죽인 왕여
General! General! General! General!
장군, 장군! 장군! 장군!
I want to ask you to take care of my end.
마지막을 자네에게 부탁하고 싶은데..
Please forgive me.
용서하십시요.
No one is to retrieve the traitor's body.
그 누구도 반역죄인의 시신을 수습하지말라.
Throw it in the field as food for the birds and the beasts.
들판에 버려두어 들짐승과 날짐승의 먹이로 두라.
It's an order!
어명이다!
Our General...
아이고...
God of Heavens! Our General.
천지신명님! 우리 장군님...
The souls of your people are saving you.
너의 백성의 염원이 너를 살리는구나
Only the Goblin's bride can pull out that sword.
오직 도깨비 신부만이 그 검을 뽑을 것이다.
If the sword is pulled out, you will return to naught and be at peace.
검을 뽑으면 무(無)로 돌아가 편안하리라.
Go-Gob-Goblin.
도깨비다!
Do you know what happens when humans are no better than beasts?
인간이 짐승보다 못하면 어찌 되는 줄 아느냐
They will meet a god with rage.
분노한 신을 만나게 되는 것이다.
How dare you! Who are you to belch such a blasphemous aura out?
대관절 뭐하는 자인데 이리도 불경스러운 기운을 내뿜는 것이야?!
You... !
나..나는...
I...
내가
[Not being able to get revenge against Wang Yeo]
왕여를 향한 복수는 하지 못하고
am late.
늦었구나.
[Goblin Kim Shin who lives forever holding onto all the painful memories of his life]
가슴 아픈 생의 기억을 고스란히 갖고 불멸을 살게 된 도깨비 김신
In the end, my life was a punishment.
결국 나의 삶은 벌이였다.
I was not able to forget a single death.
그 누구의 죽음도 잊히지 않았다.
[Not knowing if it's a reward or a punishment]
상인지 벌인지도 모를
[The Goblin who lives a life that does not age nor die]
늙지도 죽지도 않는 생을 사는 도깨비
Were you at peace?
그간 편안하였느냐?
I am still alive and still not at peace.
나는 여태 이렇게 살아있고, 편안하지 못하였는데.
[939 years of living life that's not like  living nor dying.]
죽은 것도 산 것도 아닌 939년의 세월
Please let me find a part-time job and do something about my aunt and the family. [Hearing a voice at the end of a long, long time]
알바 꼭 구하게 해주시고, 이모네 식구 좀 어떻게 해주시고
Please do something about this trashy situation.
그지같은 상황에서 저 좀 어떻게..
Even if it's worth 10 won... please...
십원 한 개라도 제발..
[Ji Eun Tak celebrates her 19th birthday alone]
홀로 19번째 생일을 맞이한 지은탁
Is it you?
너야?
That startled me.
아, 깜짝이야.
Me?
저요?
I'm asking if the one who called me was you.
날 불러낸게 너냐고.
I didn't call you, though.
저 안 불렀는데요?
You did.
네가 불렀어.
I really did not.
저 진짜 안불렀다니까요?
You called me, for sure. Think about how you called me.
네가 불렀어 분명. 생각해 어떻게 불렀는지.
Earnestly?
절실하게?
See, it's you.
거봐 너야.
That startled me!
아, 깜짝아!
[Whenever she blows out the fire on a candle, she summons the Goblin, wherever, whenever.]
촛불을 불어 끄면 언제 어디서든 도깨비 소환
You are eating something really expensive.
완전 비싼 거만 먹어.
[Awkward]
뻘쭘
I thought this wouldn't work.
이건 안될 줄 알았는데..
Why do it when you thought it wouldn't work?
안될 줄 알았는데 왜 해?!
Mister, are you perhaps a goblin?
아저씨 혹시 도깨비 아니에요?
What are you?
너 뭐야?
It's a bit embarrassing to say it with my own mouth, but I am the Goblin's bride.
제 입으로 말하긴 좀 뭐한데. 전 도깨비신부 거든요.
Tell me everything you see in me.
나한테 보이는거 말해봐.
You're tall.
키가 크시네요.
And?
또?
Your clothes look expensive.
옷이 비싸보여요.
If that's all that you see then you are not the Goblin's bride. You have no use to a goblin.
나한테 보이는게 그게 다라면, 넌 도깨비신부가 아니야. 도깨비에게 넌 효용가치가 없거든.
Don't have useless hopes and call for me.
괜한 헛된 희망으로 날 불러내지 말라고.
No, no! Cancel, cancel! No!
아니야, 아니야, 아니야, 취소야 취소! 아니야!
You must be reading a book.
책보고 계셨나봐요.
I am always near a book and I have deep taste in music and art.
늘 책을 가까이 하고, 음악과 그림에 조예가 깊은 편이야.
I'm sorry for disturbing you when you were reading.
죄송하네요 독서하시는데 방해해서.
That... don't you see anything unique?
그, 뭐 이렇게 특이한거 안보여?
Something that looks really painful.
되게 아파보이는 뭐 그런거.
Ah... that.
아, 그거?
- You see it? - And I thought it was something.
-보여? -난 또 뭐라고.
Do you see it? You don't see it, do you?
보이냐고? 너 안보이지?
Do you see it or not?
보여, 안 보여?
What happens if I see it?
보이면 어떻게 되는건데요?
- Why are you asking? You don't see it anyway. - Who said I can't see it?
-왜 물어? 어짜피 안 보이는데. -누가 안보인데?
You can't see it.
너 안보여.
I really can see it. I can really see it.
보이는데 진짜? 진짜 보여요!
This sword.
이 검!
Then what am I now?
그럼 나 이제 뭐에요?
Am I still not the Goblin's bride?
나 아직도 도깨비신부 아니에요?
I think you are.
맞는거같아.
So then, have I now become useful?
그러면 나 효용가치 그거 생기는 건가?
Then will you not leave now?
그럼 아저씨 이제 안 떠나는 거에요?
For now.
일단은..
But then... I'm trying to learn more about you. How did you get stabbed with the sword?
근데요, 제가 아저씨에 대해 좀 알아봤는데요. 검은 왜 꽂게 된거에요?
Did you do it yourself? Others?
본인이? 남이?
By someone I never thought would do that.
절대 그럴리 없다고 생각한 사람이.
It must be a really painful story.
되게 아픈얘기구나.
What about your age? How old exactly are you?
나이는요? 정확히 몇 살이예요?
939 years old.
939살
But still... it must be nice to live for long.
그래도 오래 살면 좋겠다.
You don't age, you have a lot of money and you even met your bride.
늙지도 않고, 돈도 많고, 이렇게 신부도 만나고.
Do you want to live long? Even if everything flows and you're the only one in place?
넌 오래 살고 싶어? 너만 멈춰있고 다 흘러가 버려도.
I have you.
아저씨 있잖아요.
Since you will be there, I think living long won't be so bad.
♫ It`s a beautiful life 난 너의 곁에 있을게 ♫ 아저씨 계속 있을거니까, 전 오래 살아도 좋을거 같은데?
♬   I will be by your side   ♬
♫ 너의 곁에 있을게 ♫
♬   This beautiful life   ♬
♫ It`s a beautiful life  ♫
[The Goblin who starts to have unidentifiable feelings the more he spends time with Eun Tak.]
♫ 너의 뒤에 서 있을게  ♫
♬   Beautiful life   ♬
♫ beautiful life  ♫
The size of the mass is not proportional to its volume.
질량의 크기는 부피와 비례하지 않는다.
That tiny girl as small as a violet...
제비꽃같이 그 조그마한 그 계집애가
That girl who flows like flower petals...
꽃잎같이 그 하늘거리는 그 계집애가
She is pulling me with more force than Earth's gravity.
지구보다 더 큰 질량으로 나를 끌어당긴다.
My heart continued to swing like a pendulum from sky to ground.
심장이 하늘에서 땅까지 아찔한 진자운동을 계속하였다.
Mister, are you mad?
아저씨 화났어요?
It was first love.
첫사랑이었다.
That child is the only one who can end my life,
그 아이만이 날 죽게 할 수 있는데
but she keeps on making me want to live.
그 아이가 자꾸 날 살게해.
Isn't that funny?
웃기지?
Don't kid yourself. Even without her, you lived fine.
착각하지마. 걔 없을 때도 너 잘 살았어.
Really?
그랬나?
[The happier he becomes, the worse the pain.]
행복할수록 고통은 더해가고
Only the Goblin's bride...
오직 도깨비 신부만이
can pull out the sword.
그 검을 뽑을 것이다
When she pulls out the sword, you will become dust and finally be at peace.
검을 뽑으면 무(無)로 돌아가 편안하리다.
I have made my decision.
나는 결심했다.
I should disappear...
나는 사라져야겠다.
before I want to live more,
더 살고 싶어지기 전에
and before I become happier...
더 행복해지기 전에
for you...
너를 위해
this is the decision I have to make...
내가 해야 하는 선택.
ending this life.
이 생을 끝내는 것
Oh, my god!
우와!
There's always a cool place behind your door. [The Goblin decides to draw out the sword.]
아저씨 문 뒤에 항상 멋진곳이 있네요?
But this must be a very special place. Seeing how you have to get the sword pulled out here.
근데 여기 되게 특별한데 인가봐요? 검빼는게 꼭 여기여야 하는거 보면?
My beginning and my end.
나의 시작과 끝.
Awesome.
대박.
It's the first snow, Mister.
첫눈이에요 아저씨!
Now, let's become pretty.
자, 그럼 이제 이뻐져봅시다.
And your last words?
마지막으로 남기실 말은?
The time I shared together with you
너와 함께한 시간 모두
was wonderful. Because the day was good...
눈부셨다
because the day was bad...
날이 좋지않아서
because the day was good enough...
날이 적당해서
I loved each and every day.
모든 날이 좋았다
[The Goblin's bride's hands cannot grab the sword]
도깨비 신부 손에 잡히지 않는 검
No... this... why can't I grab it?
아니 이게 왜 안잡히지?
I can see it but why can't I pull it out?
이거 보이는데도 안 뽑히죠 왜?
Did you put enough strength in your hands?
너 손에 힘줬어?
I got it. I think this is that thing. I know it.
나 알았어요, 이거 그건거 같아요 저 알아요.
What is it?
뭔데?
A kiss.
입맞춤요.
I was in a hurry, so please understand.
너무 급해서 그런거니까 이해해주세요.
Open your eyes.
눈 떠.
This is me with them open...
이게 다 뜬건데요?
[One day, Sam Shin Grandma came to see the Goblin.]
어느 날 도깨비를 찾아온 삼신할머니
Quickly pull the sword. Pull it out
빨리 그 검 뽑아, 검 뽑고
and return to dust.
무(無)로 돌아가.
You came out of nowhere and the first thing you're telling me is to die....
다짜고짜 나타나서 하시는 말씀이 죽으라니.
You've lived long enough,
너 살만큼 살았잖아.
but that child hasn't. If you don't become dust,
근데 그 아이는 아니거든. 네가 무(無)로 돌아가지 않으면
Eun Tak will die.
은탁이가 죽어.
If she fails to execute her task as a tool, the reason for her existence will disappear, because then there won't be a reason to why she should exist.
도구로써의 역할을 다 하지 못하면 존재가치가 사라져. 존재의 이유가 없으니까.
Therefore, if she doesn't pull the sword out, she will keep on facing death.
때문에 검을 안빼면 그 아이앞에 자꾸 죽음이 닥쳐올거야.
I'm sure she already has multiple times.
이미 여러번 그랬을껄?
This thing!
진짜 이 년이!
Goodbye!
잘가요!
Even you almost killed her with your own hands...
너조차 한 번 죽일뻔 했었지, 네 손으로 직접.
♬ When I close my eyes ♬
♫ 나의 두 눈을 감으면  ♫
♬ Your eyes appear ♬
♫ 떠오르는 그 눈동자  ♫
♬ Because my heart keeps on aching, I was hoping to forget ♬
♫ 자꾸 가슴이 시려서 잊혀지길 바랬어 ♫
- So... ♬ If it's a dream ♬
♫ 꿈이라면  ♫ 그러니까
- if I pull out that sword, ♬  I wish I could wake up ♬
♫  이제 깨어났으면 ♫ 제가 그 검을 빼면
- Mister will die? ♬ Are you really ♬
♫  제발, 정말 네가 ♫ 아저씨가 죽는다구요?
[The harsh fate is that one of them has to die.] ♬ My destiny. You are falling you ♬
♫ 나의 운명인 걸까 넌 Falling You ♫
♬ You are Falling You ♬
♫ 넌 Falling You ♫
Did you really love me?
나 사랑하게 됐어요?
No?
아니에요?
You didn't do even that?
그것조차 안했어요?
I'm scared. I'm so scared.
무서워, 너무 무섭다.
I wish I could stay alive...
계속 살아있었으면 좋겠어.
with you.
너와 같이
♬   I’ll certainly find you  ♬
♫ 내가 꼭 찾아낼게 ♫
♬   I’ll recognize you. Wherever you are  ♬
♫ 내가 널 알아볼게 ♫
- I have something to confess... ♬  Whatever you look like   ♬
♫ 니가 있는 곳 어디든 ♫ 고백할거 있어요.
- I can't pull out the sword for you anymore. ♬   I’ll certainly recognize you   ♬
♫ 꼭 알아볼게 ♫ 나 이제 아저씨 검 못빼줘요.
- Even if you smile, I won't pull it out. ♬   I’ll certainly remember  ♬
♫ 내가 꼭 기억할게 ♫ 웃어도 안 빼줄거에요.
- In my eyes, Mister is still very pretty. ♬   I’ll remember. I’ll recognize you  ♬
♫ 내가 널 바라볼게 ♫ 제 눈엔 아저씨 지금도 엄청 이뻐요.
It's a new face. It's the one that I told you about before, who was wandering around for a long time.
뉴페이스야, 내가 전에 말한 그 구천 오래 떠돈 노하우있다는.
[However, the misfortune continues]
하지만 계속되는 불행
[Goblin Kim Shin's enemy, Park Joong Hun's soul, appears.]
도깨비 김신의 원수인 박중헌의 혼이 나타나는데
Nice to meet you.
반갑다.
You are the Goblin's bride?
네가 그 도깨비 신부구나.
I...
제가
met some sort of soul.
어떤 망자랑 마주쳤는데
Anyhow, I think it was Park Joong Hun.
아무래도 박중헌인거 같아요.
You avoided me for 900 years...
구백년을 피해다녔는데
you shall answer why you appeared before me now.
이제와 내눈에 띈 이유를 답해야 할 것 이다.
You are laughable for not being able to recognize your enemy beside you.
원수를 지척에 두고도 못 알아보는 꼴이 우스워서
I am here to let you know personally.
내 친히 알려주려 합니다.
You can't kill me with a mere sword.
그깐 물의 검으로 나는 못벤다.
Do you know who that Grim Reaper beside you is?
네 놈 곁에 있는 그 저승사자가 누구인줄 아느냐?
He is precisely...
그 자가 바로
Wang Yeo.
'왕여'다.
[The closest person to him, the Grim Reaper, is truly Wang Yeo, the enemy]
가장 가까이에 있던 저승사자가 원수 왕여였다는 사실
[After 939 years,]
939년을 지나
[Kim Shin and Wang Yeo meet.]
드디어 만난 김신과 왕여
General Kim Shin...
상장군 김신
is here to meet Your Highness.
폐하를 뵙습니다.
In the end...
결국
am I him?
내가 그인가?
I remember that memory every moment of every day.
나는 여전히 매일매일 그 생지옥 속의 일분일초를 기억하는데
But since you have no memory,
기억이 없으니 넌
it must be comfortable for you. What must I do?
편하겠구나. 나는 어찌해야 할까..
What must I do with him?
그자를 어찌해야 할까.
Listen carefully. I will be calling in a moment. [The Goblin found a way to get rid of Park Joong Hun]
잘 들어, 내가 잠시 후에 전화를 할거야.
-Then you should summon me right away. - That's a piece of gum. (easy)
-그럼 넌 날 즉시 소환해. -껌이죠.
♬   How can I get over you   ♬
♬  How can I get over you  ♬
♬   Why do we have to be apart?  ♬
♬  Why do we have to be apart?  ♬
I'll come back.
갔다 올게.
[A sudden appearance in front of him]
눈앞에 나타난 간신
So should we go to our last war?
우리의 마지막 전장으로 가볼까?
How will you know where I will be going?
내가 어디로 갈 줄 알고?
Don't be resentful. This is your fate.
원망마라 이게 네 운명이니.
[Eun Tak gets possessed]
간신이 빙의된 은탁
You will die by my hands.
내 손에 죽겠구나
Park Joong Hun. Park Joong Hun.
박중헌, 박중헌
Park Joong Hunn!
박중헌!
So I go like this.
이리 가는구나
However, it is not for naught since I killed you again.
허나 허망하지 않다. 보아라
In the end...
결국
it is destruction.
파국이다.
No! No!
안 돼, 안 돼!
Meeting you in my life...
널 만난 내 생은
[Meeting you was my life's reward.]
널 만난 내 생은 상이었다
Was a reward...
상이었다.
I don't want this.
싫어요!
Please.
제발..
[In the end the Goblin ceases to exist]
결국 소멸해버린 도깨비
♬ When I close my eyes  ♬
♫ 나의 두 눈을 감으면 ♫
♬ Your eyes appear. Because my heart keeps on aching ♬
♫ 떠오르는 그 눈동자 자꾸 가슴이 시려서 ♫
♬ I was hoping to forget ♬
♫ 잊혀지길 바랬어 ♫
♬ If it's a dream ♬
♫ 꿈이라면 ♫
Your order
주문하신
of heaven is here.
천국 나왔습니다.
Please send it to the dry cleaners.
세탁소 갖다 주세요.
Now that we see this auspicious hat, you know who the next character I'm about to introduce is, right? [The character of the auspicious hat]
자, 이 상서로운 갓을 보니 다음에 소개해드릴 주인공이 누군지 아시겠죠?
That is the Grim Reaper.
바로 저승사자입니다.
What a dignified character, huh? At the end of life...
참 품격있는 인물이죠. 생의 끝자락
Somewhere between the boundary of life and death, he meets countless souls
생(生)과 사(死), 그 경계 어딘가에서 수많은 망자들을 만나고
and erases their memories.
기억을 지웁니다.
If you can count oblivion as God's kind consideration...
망각또한 신의 배려답게 말이죠.
However during this time he is living having forgotten his memories.
하지만 그 또한 자신의 기억을 잊고 삽니다.
Before those memories are awakened by a ring.
반지로 전생의 기억을 소환되기 전까지 말입니다.
How much is this?
이거 얼마에요?
[Ring]
반지
Over there... Over there.
저기... 저기...
Hello? 911? We're at the intersection at Yuksam Station.
여보세요 119죠? 여기 역삼사거리인데요.
Why am I there?
내가 왜 저기..
Hwang Mi Young, 25 years old. [The Grim Reaper's day begins as he welcomes the dead]
황미영, 25세.
Year of Gaechoong, April, day Eulsa, born on the fourth hour. Cause of death: suffocation.
계축년 정사월 을사일 신서시 출생, 사인 질식사.
[Sending off another dead soul serving a tea of oblivion]
망각의 차를 건네며 또 한 명의 망자를 떠나보내는데
Drink it.  It will make you forget this life's memories.
마셔요, 이승의 기억을 잊게 해줍니다.
- If I don't drink it? - If you don't drink it, you will end up regretting it.
- 안 마시면.. - 안 마신걸 후회하게 되겠죠.
Sunbae, they say that if you commit a really big sin in your previous life you become a Grim Reaper.
선배님 전생에 큰 죄를 지으면 저승사자가 된다는데
What kind of sin and how serious do you think it was?
대체 무슨 죄를 얼마나 크게 지은 걸까요?
I'm sure it's the will of God. It's just that, returning the memory that one lost...
다 신의 뜻이겠지. 다만 잃은 기억을 다시 돌려준
I'm just curious as to what the will of God is in that.
신의 뜻이 무엇일지 궁금할 뿐.
[The Grim Reaper quietly sends off numerous dead]
묵묵히 수많은 망자 떠나보내는 저승사자
You got heaven.
천국 나왔습니다.
Grim Reaper?
저승사자?
Goblin?
도깨비?
What a terribly vulgar hat you wear.
매우 상스러운 갓을 썼군.
How did you come to be in my house?
-내 집엔 어쩐일로? -이미
I signed the contract. [In the meantime, the mysterious arrangement of living with the Goblin begins]
계약서에 도장을 다 찍어서.
I hope it wasn't an important document.
중요한 서류는 아니었길 바라.
I'm sure you know very well what a contract with the Grim Reaper means.
사자와의 계약이 어떤건지 잘 알텐데?
I guess it can't be helped.  We have a lot of empty rooms. Make yourself at home.
할 수 없네, 빈 방 많으니까 써. 내 집이다 생각하고.
- It's my house.
-내 집이야.
If you think you can kick out the Goblin from his turf, go for it. Fighting.
도깨비 터에서 도깨비를 쫓아낼 수 있으면 어디 한 번 화이팅.
Look at it in the mirror, Oppa.
거울에 한 번 대봐요 오빠?
How much is this?
이거 얼마에요?
[He faces the woman of his fate]
운명의 여인과 마주하게 된다
You're crying?
울어?
Should I get something else?
양보해줘요?
I'm Sunny.
써니에요.
Hey there!  Are we not going to greet each other?
저기요, 인사 안해요 우리?
Are we not going to ask about each other? Not even talk?
안부 안 묻구요? 얘기는 안하나요?
- Hello. -Tell me honestly,
-안녕하세요. -솔직히 말해보세요.
you've forgotten my name, right?
제 이름 까먹었죠?
- Seon Hee. - Not Seon Hee, Sunny!
-선희요. -선희아니고 써니요!
But now that I think about it, I don't even know your name. What is your name?
근데 생각해 보니까 난 그 쪽 이름도 모르는데, 이름이 뭐에요?
Na-Name?
이..이름이요?
Not your name, a man's name that women like.
네 이름말고 여자들이 좋아하는 남자이름.
If it's a name that women like, typically there are these three names.
여자들이 좋아하는 이름이라면, 대표적으로 이 세 명이 있죠.
Hyun Bin. Won Bin. Kim Woo Bin.
현빈, 원빈, 김옥빈.
Bin...
빈.
Today, do you have a name?
오늘은 이름있어요?
Kim. Woo. Bin.
김우빈.
You said he works in a service industry. He must be a waiter.
서비스직 이라더니 웨이터인가봐.
- Did you buy that ring? - No, a man gave it to me.
-반지 사셨어요? -아니, 남자가 줬어.
By the way, it looks like a really old ring.
근데 이거 되게 오래된 반지같아요.
Uncle.
삼촌.
Your uncle's not here. He went out.
니네 삼촌 없어, 나갔어.
Oh, really? Then, please give this to my uncle.
그래요? 그럼 이것 좀 삼촌한테 전해주세요.
[The woman in the scroll that released the Grim Reaper's emotions]
저승사자의 감정을 폭발시킨 족자 속 여인
Who is it? Is it Uncle's ex-girlfriend?
누구지? 삼촌 옛날 여친인가?
Looks like an antique.
걍 골동품같기도 하고?
Why did you look at my painting? He said he tried to stop you.
너 내 그림 왜봤냐? 얘는 말렸다는데.
Who is the woman in the painting? [The Grim Reaper is curious about his unexplainable feelings]
근데 누구야? 이 그림 속 여인.
She's my sister.
내 누이야.
- Uncle, you had a sister? - Have you ever seen my sister?
-삼촌 누나가 있었어? -진짜 내 여동생 본 적 있어?
Think carefully and figure out where you saw her.
잘 생각해봐 어디서 봤는지.
Did you ever want to get your memory back?
근데 넌 기억을 찾고 싶다는 생각 한 적 없어?
[He wants to get back his lost memory]
잊혀진 기억을 찾고 싶어 하고
No, I didn't.
없지.
What's a forgotten memory? Isn't it same as having no memory?
잊은 기억이라는게 뭐야, 없는 기억과 마찬가지 아니야?
I never had one to begin with. Why would I now...
애초에 없었던 걸 왜 굳이..
♬  I love you, love you, love you  ♬
♫ I love u love u love u ♫
♫ I could feel that we are meant to be ♫
♫ 인연인 걸 느꼈죠 ♫
The kiss of the Grim Reaper...
저승사자의 키스는
brings back the memory of your previous life.
전생을 기억나게 합니다.
In your previous life...
당신의 전생에
I'm afraid of who I was.
내가 무엇이었을지 두렵습니다.
[Two people who had been connected as a married couple in their previous life]
전생에 부부의 연을 맺었던 두 사람
The woman who loves you, Your Majesty...
폐하를 사랑하는 여인은
is the sister of the traitor.
대역죄인의 누이입니다.
[Destiny of a previous life that ended in tragedy]
♫ 바라보면 ♫
♫ I don’t know why ♫
♫ 왠지 몰라도 ♫
♫ Going around and round, were you coming back to me? ♫
♫ 돌고 돌아 내게 오고 있었나요 ♫
Everything I saw...
♫ 피해지지 않는 그 사랑 ♫ 내가 본 것들..
What is that?
뭐에요?
Will you look at into eyes?
내 눈을 좀 보시겠어요?
Let only the happy moments remain...
행복으로 반짝거리던 순간들만 남기고
Difficult and...
힘들고
sad moments... forget all that.
슬픈 순간들은 다 잊어요.
Whether it's in your previous life or current life.
전생이든, 현생이든.
And...
그리고
forget me, too.
나도 잊어요.
As expected, I...
역시 나는
must've been her worst memory.
가장 나쁜 기억인 모양이다.
To you and...
당신에게서도
to Kim Shin as well.
김신, 그 자 에게서도.
We're the auditors of the afterlife.
저승부 감사팀이다.
You have been found to have used your powers for personal reasons while carrying out your duty. [The punishment for him]
그대는 차사직을 수행하면서 사사로이 능력을 쓴 사실이 확인되었다.
Your identity was revealed, yet you didn't do anything about it. You returned the previous life's memory to a human, among others...
존재를 들키고도 조치하지 않은 것, 인간에게 전생을 돌려준 것 등.
You two had a fight. You didn't see anything.
둘이 싸운거다, 너흰 아무것도 보지 못했다.
Say, "I'll get going first."
'먼저 갈게' 라고 해.
I'll get going first.
먼저 갈게요.
I'm the Grim Reaper.
저는 저승사자입니다.
Do you acknowledge everything?
모두 인정하는가?
- I acknowledge. - Since you acknowledge this...
-인정합니다. -본인도 인정한바
we will give you a heavy punishment. Immediately, acknowledge the strictness of the matter.
이에 중징계를 내리니 사안의 엄중함을 직시하라.
Face your sins again. That is... [He regains all the forgotten memories of his past life]
다시 너의 죄와 대면하라. 그것이
the heavy punishment for violating all these strict rules.
이 모든 규율위반의 엄중한 벌이다.
[Wang Yeo lives a weary life after his queen dies]
황후를 떠나보낸 후 피폐한 삶을 살던 왕여
The health of the king is suffering and the people are concerned.
폐하의 심신이 미령하여 만 백성이 근심이다.
Starting tomorrow, decrease his meals and give him herbal tonics.
명일부터 수라를 줄이고 탕약을 드리라.
Even if it's bitter to your taste, please take it.
입에 써도 드시옵고
Keep your mind and body clear and be strong.
옥채와 정신을 맑게하시어 강건함을..
If I'm this strong...
이 정도 강건함이면
would you be satisfied?
되시겠소?
[He misses his queen]
내내 황후를 그리워하고
[Even in the present life he can't forget her]
현생에서도 그녀를 잊지 못하는데
Why do you keep on following me around?
♫ 이제서야 왜 ♫ 왜 자꾸 따라다녀요?
It's been a few days already.
♫ 내게 왔죠 ♫ 벌써 며칠 됐잖아요.
Are you a stalker?
♫ I love u ♫ 스토커에요?
Thanks to you it felt like I was dating...
♫ 인연인 걸 느꼈죠 난 ♫ 덕분에 데이트하는 기분이었네요 나는.
- with you, Kim Woo Bin. - How do you remember?
-김우빈씨랑. -어떻게 기억을..
You didn't hypnotize me very well.
당신이 최면을 잘못걸었으니까?
How could I be left with only the happy moments,
행복했던 순간들만 남기래놓고
and forget you?
당신을 잊으라니
The two don't match.
순서가 안 맞지.
Every day...
매일이
bitterly...
사무치게
I missed you.
그리워서
What did you plan to do?
그럴걸 뭐하러.
I was foolish.
어리석어서
Please wake up quickly.
빨리 좀 깨닫지.
Here.
자요.
Let's really break up, us.
진짜 헤어져요 우리.
I don't want to fall in love in this life.
이번 생에는 안 반할래.
The punishment that I can give you,
내가 당신한테 줄 수 있는 벌이
there's nothing but this.
이것밖에 없어.
Goodbye, Your Majesty.
굿바이 폐하.
[Two people who end up parting again.]
또다시 이별을 하게 된 두 사람
[The love story within the Goblin.]
도깨비 내외 사랑 이야기
[Oppa's smile]
오빠 미소
What kind of God is like this? It didn't come true you know! Boyfriend!
무슨 수호신이이래? 안 이루어졌잖아요, 남친!
He's here you know, your boyfriend!
여기있잖아 네 남친!
- Here? Where? Here? Where? - Here! Beside you! Me!
-여기 어디, 여기 어디? -여기 네 앞에 나!
Oh, dirty! I'll have to cut it off! [To a severe cry baby]
아, 더러워 잘라 버려야 돼!
Sterilizer. [Sterilizer.]
소독.
[He is a serious chicken but...]
심각한 겁쟁이지만
First snow inside the theater...
영화관에 내린 첫눈..
You have to come with me.
넌 나랑 같이 가야지.
Where are you going to take my Mister? I'm a bit sensitive about that.
우리 아저씨 어디 데려가시게요? 나 그거 좀 민감한데?
She said, "My..."
'우리'라고 했다.
You're so pathetic.
아저씨 너무 불쌍하다.
I keep my word... Can't you just... [Give and Take]
언행일치를 좀 해주면..
If you're always like that for free, what am I supposed to do?
자꾸 맨입으로 그러시면 어떡해요?
No, but what is it that you want?
아니 네가 원하는게 뭔데?
Can you not imagine buying a house, with money, full of jewelry,
보석 가득한 집을 돈으로 사서
and putting in some love for me? [Can't you give me a house full of jewelry with love?]
사랑을 담아 주실 생각은 못하시는 거에요?
Just go.
너 가.
Don't eat mine, eat yours.
내 꺼 먹지말고 네 꺼 먹어.
- I ate it all. - Don't keep on smiling while eating.
-내 꺼 다 먹었어요. -웃으면서 계속 먹지말고.
How can a person's heart change?
사람마음이 어떻게 변해요?
- If you still don't know that, what am I supposed to do? - Seriously...
-그걸 아직도 모르면 어떡해. -대박.
[Very sulky Eun Tak]
잔뜩 뿔난 은탁
I think you just did that deliberately...
방금 일부러 그런거 같은데?
It wasn't, though.
아닌데요?
I'm all covered in water though, I'm sure you can see...
나 물 다묻었는데 보일텐데?
- If you're dissatisfied about something, tell me. - Ah, dissatisfied! You spoke well!
-불만있으면 얘기를 해. -아, 불만? 말씀 잘 하셨네.
I thought you said that all the time you spent with me was wonderful.
나와 함께한 시간이
Now as well.
눈부셨다면서요.
Incomparably wonderful.
지금도 속도 없이 눈부시다고.
January 1st New Year! I've just become an adult!
1월 1일 새해! 저 방금 어른됐어요!
So I put on my clothes and came just like this, since earlier!
그래서 옷 딱 입고, 아까부터 내가!
You'll be okay, righ-?
너 괜찮겠..
If there was just one more thing it would be perfect. [Just one thing missing]
딱 하나면 더 있으면 완벽한데.
First kiss. [A kiss]
첫키스요.
[Grim Reaper's love story, beginner in dating]
연애 초보 저승사자의 순애보
[After knowing nothing but his job for 300 years]
300년 동안 일 밖에 몰랐던
Year Moo In, Month Eul Mo, Day Gi Myo.
무인년 을묘월 기묘일
Deceased at 08:32. [A cold male Grim Reaper]
공팔시 삽십이분 사망.
It's you, right?
맞으시죠?
The face I've only seen in the painting comes to life and she's so beautiful that I'm out of my mind...
그림에서만 봤던 얼굴이 생기를 얻으니 너무 아름다워 가지고 정신이 하나도..
There's no female ghost following him around obsessing over him, right?
막 찾아오고 집착하는 여자귀신같은건 없니?
That thought comes to mind first... [Robot smile]
그 생각부터 들더라.
But.. since earlier why do you keep on smiling?
근데 아까부터 왜 자꾸 웃어요?
Am I not... cute? [Is this not cute?]
저 안 귀엽나요?
How?
어디가요?
Am I really not cute?
진짜 안 귀엽나요?
Ah, I've got goosebumps!
어, 소름돋아.
Well.. even to that extent... [Sullen]
뭐 그렇게까지..
[Haughty]
도도 도도
Those footsteps!
이 발소리!
[The Grim Reaper who knows it's her just by hearing her footsteps]
어, 어?!
Oh... where?
어어어어... 어디...?
What the hell does he do?
뭐하는 인간이야 대체?
I am a Grim Reaper.
저승사자입니다.
Shall I really kill this bastard?
이 새끼 진짜 죽여버릴까?
Seriously, just let me try and catch him.
진짜 잡히기만 해봐.
[If he gets caught he'll die]
걸리면 죽는다
[I will devote my body to protect my woman]
내 여자는 내 몸 바쳐 지킨다
- I missed you. - This guy... I did as well.
-보고싶어서. -참나, 저도요.
- What does Woo Bin like? - Sunny.
-우빈씨는 뭐 좋아하세요? -써니 씨요.
- A hobby or that kind of thing...
-취미 뭐 그런거요.
Like dramas, I'm recklessly attracted to you.
드라마만큼 맹목적으로 끌립니다.
Crazy.
미친다.
What am I supposed to do if you suddenly come and find me like this?
이렇게 갑자기 찾아오면 어떡해요.
Since I've just come out of my home, I don't have any makeup on.
집에 있다 나와서 쌩얼이잖아요.
[A face without makeup??]
♫ 또 식은땀이 흐르네 ♫
The Goblin who needs a human bride in order to end his everlasting life.
불멸을 삶을 끝내기 위해 인간신부가 필요한 도깨비.
And the Grim Reaper who strangely began to live together with him.
그와 기묘한 동거를 시작한 기억상실증 저승사자.
In front of them...
그런 그들앞에
a girl who insists that she's the Goblin bride appears.
자신이 도깨비신부라 주장하는 소녀가 나타나며 벌어지는 신비로운
Mysterious romance tale.
낭만설화.
This lonesome and brilliant fantasy...
이 쓸쓸하고 찬란한 신 판타지는 말이죠
Like the life of this 10 won coin,
이 십원짜리 인생.
she only wanted enough help worth 10 won.
십원짜리 만큼의 도움만 받고 싶었을 뿐인데
Because of a 19-year-old girl who is marked with an enormous amount of responsibility,
십억 년만큼의 억겁의 낙인이 찍혀버린 소녀때문에
it makes us laugh and cry even more.
우릴 더욱 웃고 울게 만드는 겁니다.
And the viewer rating heightens as her fate becomes even more brutal... [A confident girl who stands strong in the face of her fate that is undeniably disgraceful]
또한 그녀의 운명이 가혹해 질 수록, 시청률이 올라가는
It's quite ironic, isn't it?
참 아이러니하죠?
You understand what I'm saying, right?
제 말 무슨말인지 알죠?
The Goblin's bride... [The Goblin's bride is born.]
-도깨비 신부다. -도깨비 신부가 태어났어. -어깨에 도깨비 낙인이있어.
Only the Goblin's bride
오직 도깨비 신부만이
will be able to pull out that sword.
그 검을 뽑을 것이다.
[Eun Tak grows up to be a 19 year old girl]
19세 소녀로 훌쩍 자란 은탁
Please eat your breakfast, one man and two women.
아침드세요 남자 하나에 여자 두 분.
All she's doing is putting a meal together. What's with the fuss...
밥상 하나 차리면서 유세는.
Why seaweed soup again?
웬 미역국?
Wow, has Ji Eun Tak just cooked seaweed soup because it's her birthday?
대박. 지금 지 생일이라고 미역국 끓인거야?
You're right!
맞네.
Geez, it's a day she was born a killer of her own mother...
으휴 지 엄마 잡아먹고 태어난 날이
What's there to be so proud about that she's remembering the day?
뭐가 그렇게 자랑스러워서 그걸 챙길 낯까지 있어.
Where are you escaping to now?
지금 어딜 도망가?!
After school has finished bring your bankbook and come to the bank.
학교끝나고 통장갖고 은행으로 와.
You know what will happen if you come again today without it, right?
오늘도 안 갖고오면 어떻게 되는지 알지?
I don't have a bankbook.
나한테 통장없다니까요?
How many times do I have to--
도대체 몇번을 얘기해야..
Where is your mother's insurance?
네 엄마 보험금 어딨냐고?!
You took everything, Aunt! You took everything including our house deposit!
이모가 다 뺏어갔잖아요, 전세금까지 다 빼갔잖아요!
Please let me find a part-time job and do something about my aunt and the family.
알바도 꼭 구하게 해주시구요, 이모네 식구 좀 어떻게 해주시고
Please let me have a boyfriend, as well!
저 남자친구도 꼭 좀 생기게 해주세요, 제발.
Is it you?
너야?
You surprised me.
엄마 깜짝이야.
Me?
저요?
I asked was it you who called me?
날 불러낸게 너냐고.
I didn't call you,
제가 부른게 아니구요
it's just that my eyes can see you.
그냥 제 눈에 아저씨가 보이는거에요.
- What do you mean, you can see me? - Mister, you're a ghost, you know.
-무슨 말이야 보인다는게? -아저씨 귀신이잖아요.
I see ghosts.
제가 귀신을 보거든요?
What on earth are you?
너 대체 뭐야?
What are you exactly that, when usually I should be able to, I can't see anything?
뭔데 보통은 보여야 되는게 아무것도 안보여?
What should you see, though?
뭐가 보여야 되는데요?
Your twenties, your thirties, your future.
스무살, 서른살, 너의 미래.
I guess I haven't got one. A future.
없나 보죠 미래가.
Mister, you aren't perhaps the Goblin?
아저씨 혹시 도깨비 아니에요?
What are you? What on earth are you?
너 뭐야? 너 대체 뭐야?
It's a bit weird saying it with my own mouth but..
제 입으로 말하기 좀 뭐한데.
I'm the Goblin's bride.
전 도깨비 신부거든요.
You can see it right?
보이시죠?
This? [A clear mark]
이거?
- Student. - Why are you like this? No! Why are you like this?
- 학생. - 아저씨 왜 이러세요? 아니, 왜이러세요?!
Your Aunt is worrying a lot you know!
이모가 많이 걱정하시잖아! 빨리 타!
Where did you hide the bankbook?
통장 어따 숨겼어?!
I really don't know.
저 정말 몰라요!
Why are you asking me for my aunt's debt?
이모가 진 빚을 왜 저한테 그러세요?!
You want to die?
확 뒤질려고!
Hey, you bastard, can't you drive properly?!
야, 이 새끼야 너 운전 똑바로 안해?
Quickly! Quickly!
밟아봐!
She'll stay here with us starting today.
오늘부터 여기서 같이 지낼거야.
Thank you for the meal.
잘먹었습니다.
Announcement: Please call me if something urgent comes up.
호소문, 급한 일이 있으시면 연락주세요
Please don't appear in front of me all of a sudden.
갑자기 눈 앞에 나타나지 마시구요.
Ji Eun Tak. 010-1234-1234.
지은탁 010-1234-1234.
For your information, not during my classes.
참고로 수업 중에는 안돼요.
I don't want calls while I'm working, either.
알바중에도 싫어요.
I turn it off in the library. That's all.
도서관에선 꺼놔요. 이상입니다.
Do you think she's telling us to call her?
전화를 하란 얘긴걸까?
She knows we don't have cell phones...
우리가 핸드폰 없는걸알고
Do you think she's looking down on us?
무시하는거 아닐까?
Really?
진짜?
Do you know whose fault it is that I have the mark and can see ghosts?
내가 누구때문에 이 점이 생기고, 누구때문에 귀신을 보는데요?!
What about the mark? It's pretty.
낙인 뭐 예쁘기만 하구만.
I'm telling you for your sake. For your sake!
너 위해서 얘기 한거잖아, 너 위해서!
If you're thinking of me, give me a boyfriend!
나 위할거면 남친이나 내놔요!
Part-time job, my aunt's family, a boyfriend. I didn't get my wish about a boyfriend!
알바, 이모네, 남친! 안 이루어졌잖아요 남친!
Here's your boyfriend!
여기 있잖아 네 남친!
Here? Where? Here? Where?
여기 어디에요, 어디 어디에!
Right here, in front of you. Me!
여기 네 앞에 나!
It would be natural to tap you on your shoulders, huh?
어깨도 좀 토닥해야 자연스럽겠지?
I will look at your watch and be natural.
제가 자연스럽게 시계를 좀 볼게요.
Did time stop?
시간 멈췄어요?
No.
아니?
No, no, what to do! I'm ruined!
어떡해, 어떡해 나 망했어!
I lost 30 minutes! [She's late to her college entrance exam]
30분이나 흘렀다구요!
Don't worry. Did you forget your boyfriend is a goblin?
걱정마 도깨비인거 잊었어?
♬ You're so beautiful, You're beautiful. I said you're beautiful  ♬
♫ 너 정말 이쁘다 이쁘다 이쁘다니까  ♫
♬  Why don't you believe my words? Why? ♬
♫ 왜 내 말 믿지 않는 건데 왜 ♫
♬ No matter how much I tell you and tell you again  ♬
♫ 말하고 말하고 아무리 말해도 ♫
♬ You seem angry  ♬
♫  화난 듯한 너의 그 표정 ♫
I'm back.
다녀왔습니다.
I'm so tired today for using my brain so much.
오늘 머리 너무 써서 완전 피곤..
Did you do well on your exam?
시험 잘 봤어?
It was my idea and he paid for it. Deok Hwa bought it. [Goblin prepared a cake for Eun Tak]
아이디어는 내가 내고 돈은 이 자가 내고 사온건 덕화야.
It's a cake.
우와, 케이크다.
Why are you crying? Did you ruin the exam?
왜 울어, 시험 망쳤어?
It's not that... [Eun Tak finds happiness little by little after meeting the Goblin]
그게 아니라
I'm just happy.
행복해서.
Does it hurt?
아파요?
I can hold the sword.
검이 잡혀요.
It's coming loose.
움직여요!
If I remove that sword...
그 검을 빼면
Mister will disappear?
아저씨가 없어진다고요?
The tool of extinction to end the Goblin's immortality,
도깨비의 불멸을 끝낼 소멸의 도구.
that's the fate of the Goblin's Bride.
그게 도깨비 신부의 운명이야.
What's wrong?
왜?
Don't come close.
가까이 오지마.
Boss, give me a lighter from my coat. Hurry.
사장님 제 코트에서 라이터 좀요, 빨리요.
You bitch!
네 이년!
The mark on your neck...
너 목에 낙인이..
What?
왜요?
It's almost gone.
거의 안 보여.
Really?
그래요?
Does it mean he's after me in the end?
결국 날 노린다는건가?
Jin Eun Tak!
지은탁!
Kill me, hurry.
나 베요 나 빨리.
It's over if he takes over me.
내 몸에 들어오면 끝이에요.
I know. I've never traveled overseas before. [10 years later]
그니까요, 뭐 외국에를 와봤어야죠.
That's what I mean. What do you mean going overseas at 9 o'clock?
그니까 하필 아홉시에 뭔 해외야.
When I was 29 years old, I didn't even go out to the market in front of the house.
나 스물아홉땐 집앞 슈퍼도 안나갔어.
Really?
진짜요?
Yeah, because I didn't have any plans.
어, 약속이 없어서.
CEO, over here.
대표님 여기요!
There are some curious factors that come up while watching the Goblin.
도깨비를 보고 있자면 드는 궁금증이 있죠?
This is a love story and a melodrama.
이건 사랑이야기고 멜로드라마일 뿐인데
Why do we look back to our lives while watching the drama...
우리는 왜 드라마를 보면서 지난 인생을 뒤돌아보고
and contemplate our lives for the future? [The drama, Goblin, makes us look back at our lives]
앞으로의 삶에 대해서 고민하게 될까요?
That's probably because the lines make us question continuously about life and death.
그것은 아마도 삶과 죽음에 대해서 끈임없이 질문하게 만드는 아름다운
Beautiful and memorable lines. [Memorable lines that are only found in Goblin]
그리고 주옥같은 대사들 때문이 아닐까요?
Among the many...
그 중에서 백미는요
I think it's what Deok Hwa, whom I look after, has said that's beautiful.
제가 모시고 있는 덕화도련님의 한마디가 아닐까 생각이 듭니다.
"Fate is the question I threw out there. You find your answers."
운명은 내가 던진 질문일 뿐, 답은 그대들이 찾아라.
What are your thoughts right now?
여러분께서는 지금 어떤 생각을 하고 계시는지요.
Whoever's life it may be, there is a moment God dwells in it.
누구의 인생이건 신이 머물다 가는 순간이있다.
Grandma, you don't age at all.
할머니는 어쩜 늙지를 않네?
Could you look after my Eun Tak here and there?
오다가다 우리 은탁이 좀 들여다 봐주면 안되나?
Why would I look after your daughter?
니 딸년을 내가 왜?
Give her some leftover cabbage and spinach.
배추도 남으면 좀 주고, 시금치도 좀 주고.
You should've died together then. Why is she living longer?
그러게 그 때 같이 죽지 뭐하러 더 살아가지고.
You told me to pray earnestly.
할머니가 알려줬잖아요 간절히 빌라고.
Mister, who are you?
아, 아저씨 누구세요?
But... you shouldn't have been born...
근데 넌 어째서 태어나지 못했을 애가
- Go. Leave this child alone. - Grandma!
-가, 이 아이는 놔두고. -할머니!
Is this child in your book?
이 아이가 명부에 있어?
If you have a book with her name in it, bring it to me.
이 아이 이름 적힌 명부있으면 갖고 와봐.
See you again, kiddo.
또 보자, 꼬마야.
You have to hurry and move in three days. He won't find you then.
얼른 이사가야 돼 3일안에. 그래야 널 못 찾아.
But why are you telling me these things?
근데 이런거 왜 알려주시는 거에요?
Because you're pretty.
이뻐서.
When I created you...
너 점지할 때
I was happy.
행복했거든.
Here. Your birthday gift.
이거 생일선물.
You shouldn't be sick anymore. [Sam Shin takes care of all the children of the world]
이제 그만 아파야지?
Your mom is worried.
엄마 걱정하신다.
I'm going here.
여기 갈거에요.
I know where it is. Put your seatbelt on.
어딘지 알아. 안전벨트 매.
You worked hard. Your mom will be so proud.
고생 많았어. 엄마가 엄청 자랑스러워 하실 거야.
Why did you hug me?
저를 왜 안아주세요?
Because you're pretty.
이뻐서.
When I created you... I was happy.
너 점지할 때 행복했거든
I was happy.
행복했거든.
Congratulations on your graduation.
졸업 축하해.
Take out that sword quickly.
빨리 그 검 뽑아.
Take out the sword and return to naught.
검 뽑고 무(無)로 돌아가.
Isn't it ironic.
아이러니하네.
Aren't I your child?
난 당신의 아이가 아닌가?
That's why I'm telling you now,
그래서 얘기해 주는거야.
if you don't go back to nothing, Eun Tak will die.
네가 무(無)로 돌아가지 않으면 은탁이가 죽어.
You there. It's been a while, would you like to have a drink?
저기요? 오랜만인데 술 한 잔 할래요?
Since I'm very angry right now..
내가 지금 화가 많이 나서.
Finally the Goblin and the Goblin's bride have met.
드디어 도깨비와 도깨비 신부가 만났네?
It's fate.
운명이지.
But why Wang Yeo as well?
왕여는 또 왜?
Because that is also fate. [What is the identity of this man who's face-to-face with the Sam Shin Grandma?]
그 또한 운명이므로 마침 집도 구한다기에.
Enough playing around.
장난도 정도껏이야.
Because I especially love...
특별히 사랑하여.
You are the Chairman?
회장님이세요?
Chairman... Real grandson... Chaebol third generation...
회장님, 친손자 재벌 3세.
Sorry to the friend you've brought along, but what is your job?
같이 오신 친구분은 실례지만 직업이 어떻게 되시죠?
My job is a third generation Chaebol.
직업은 재벌 3세 입니다.
I am Yoo Deok Hwa.
유덕화입니다.
Here... to me... there, please!
여긴 안된다니까요? 저기 앞에 세워 주세..
Absolutely never.
절대 네버.
If you're a chaebol, of course I must drive you to the entrance of the school in a sedan and grab everyone's attention.
재벌이라하면 응당, 학교앞까지 세단을 몰아 세간의 관심을 주목시켜야 하는것.
Can you really translate that?
정말로 해석이 가능해요?
As a third generation chaebol, you should master one thousand Chinese characters for three generations... but what's this?
재벌 3세란 응당, 3세때 부터 천자문을 떼줘야.. 근데 이게 뭔데?
Your uncle's background investigation.
오빠네 삼촌 뒷조사요.
Let's see.
보자.
It's a love letter.
연서네.
A love letter?
연서요?
Living a hundred years like that, one day... one perfect day...
그렇게 100년을 살아 어느 날, 날이 적당한 어느 날.
I thought maybe, and it's as expected.
혹시나 했는데 역시나네.
Forget it.
됐어요.
I'm here. What?
나 여깄어 왜.
Never mind. Next time.
아니에요 다음에요.
Give it to me! Why are you looking at my notebook?
아, 내놔요! 왜 남의 노트를 보고 난린데?!
What's this?
너 이거 뭐야?
- It's a love letter. A love letter. - This isn't a love letter.
연서잖아요 연서.
Living a hundred years like that, one day... one perfect day...
그렇게 100년을 살아 어느 날, 날이 적당한 어느 날.
Like that, huh?
막 어?
- That's not what it says. - Deok Hwa oppa read me everything.
-그 내용 아닌데? -덕화 오빠가 다 읽어줬는데?
There's no way.
그럴 리 없는데?
That's right. That's not what it says.
그러네 그 내용 아니네.
It can't be. Now that I think about it...
아닌데? 그러고보니
Deok Hwa found me my maple leaf.
덕화 오빠가 내 단풍잎도 찾아줬는데?
The one I completely lost.
내가 완전히 잃어버린거.
This maple leaf... guess where it's from.
이 단풍 어느 동네 껀지 맞춰봐.
What's this...
뭐지?
Deok Hwa, you...
덕화 너.
I was always listening. I even gave you a chance to ask for your death.
늘 듣고 있었다. 죽음을 탄원하기에 기회도 줬다.
But why are you still alive?
헌데, 왜 아직 살아있는 것이지?
I never erased their memory. They only chose to erase their memory.
기억을 지운 적 없다. 스스로 기억을 지우는 선택을 했을 뿐.
Even so, does it seem like God's plan or a mistake?
그럼에도 신의 계획 같기도 실수 같기도 한가?
God only asks questions.
신은 그저 질문하는 자일 뿐
Fate is the question I throw out there.
운명은 내가 던지는 질문이다
As for the answer... you find it.
답은 그대들이 찾아라
There's something I didn't tell you. [Best one minute, episode 10]
내가 너한테 말하지 않은게 있어.
Sunny's face from her past life is the face of the woman in that scroll you have...
써니씨의 전생속 얼굴이, 네가 가진 그 족자속 여인의 얼굴과
It's the same face.
같았어.
Are you sure?
확실해?
She's riding in the palanquin and asks with a smile,
가마를 타고 가다 웃으며 물어
"Do I look pretty today?"
저 오늘 이쁩니까?
There's a voice that answers her question.
그녀의 물음에 대답하는 목소리가 하나 있었어.
"You look ugly."
못생겼다.
In your past life, did you see the Grim Reaper?
네 전생에 저승 그 자가 있느냐?
Look, Orebeoni. Why are you harassing me at my workplace?
이봐요 오라버니, 남의 영업장 와서 다짜고짜 이게 뭔 행패지?
I have to go home...
난 퇴근해야 하니까.
I asked you if he's Wang Yeo.
그 자가 왕여가 맞느냐고 물었다.
You...
너는
Even in this life...
이번 생에서도
You're protecting that idiot.
그 멍청이를 지키는구나.
- Have you been well?
-잘 지냈어?
You look good with Hee Jin.
희진이랑은 보기 좋더라?
That's why that day, from the rooftop...
그래서 그 날 나 옥상에서
- Is that why you pushed me off? - You pushed...
-밀었니? -밀었..
You must want to die, also.
너도 죽고 싶은거구나?
Are you still angry?
아직 화났어요?
You must be. You must be angry.
화났겠죠? 화내겠죠?
I'm not angry. I was just worried.
화 안났어 걱정만 했지.
But why does my heart feel all prickly?
근데 왜 난 마음이 막 따끔따끔거려요.
Not as much as me.
나만큼은 아닐껄?
The scenes that scored the highest rating, through the viewers replies...
최고의 시청률을 기록한 장면을 시청자 여러분들의 댓글과 함께
we've looked at them. [Memorable scenes from Goblin through the replies from the viewers]
살펴봤는데요?
Now, there are a few replies that hit home for me.
자, 그 중에서 제 마음에 꽃힌 댓글이 몇 개 있습니다.
I'll introduce them to you.
소개해드릴게요.
When Gong Yoo said, "You look ugly," my heart almost stopped for real.
공유가 못생겼다 할 때 나 레알 심정지 했음.
Sun Min, I can say the same thing. If you want your heart to stop, please say so.
선민님 저도 못생겼다 할 수 있습니다. 네, 심정지 원하시면 말씀하세요.
What should I do... my heart keeps beating too hard.
심장이가 너무 둑흔둑흔거려 어떡하지?
It says her heart keeps beating too hard. What do we do...
이 댓글에 제 심장이 너무 둑흔둑흔, 어떡하죠?
And... experiencing Goblin, I'm perceiving above 200%.
그리고 도깨비 체감 시청률은 이미 200프로 넘음.
Thank you, 200%.
200프로 감사합니다.
Everyone, I'll go to Quebec and eat beef also.
여러분 저도 퀘벡 가서 소 좀 먹고 오겠습니다.
It doesn't work for me.
전 안되네요.
Ah, then I'll go get Deok Hwa.
아, 그럼 덕화군 잡으러 갔다오겠습니다.
He's at a nightclub.
클럽에 가 계시네요.
Then, I'll just go eat beef broth soup.
그럼 그냥 설렁탕이나 먹으러가겠습니다.
It's closed.
문 닫았네.
Goblin Special, I loved every day. We're almost at the end of the program.
도깨비 스페셜: 모든 날이 좋았다. 이제 마칠 시간인데요.
Did you enjoy the scenes we prepared for you?
어떻게 저희가 마련한 영상들 마음에 드셨는지 모르겠습니다.
In our lives, there are moments God dwells with us.
우리 생에 신이 머물다가는 순간이 있다고 합니다.
Our Goblin also would like to dwell in your life.
저희 '도깨비' 역시 여러분들 생에 머물다 가고 싶습니다.
The remaining three episodes, please watch to the end and cheer us on, everyone.
남은 3회 여러분 끝까지 지켜봐주시고 응원해주시길 바랍니다.
Please do a cheer asking the viewer to watch Goblin.
'도깨비' 앞으로 많이 봐 달라고 응원 한 번 해주세요.
- A cheer? - I heard you're a good dancer.
-응원이요? -춤을 잘 추신다 하던데.
If we score highest in the history of tvN, I'll do the TT dance by TWICE.
tvn 최고 시청률 갱신하게 되면 제가 트와이스 TT안무를 추는것으로.
It was a teaser. Please watch us to the very end.
티저였습니다. 끝까지 지켜봐주십시요.
I'm Secretary Kim. Thank you.
지금까지 김비서였습니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
[Goblin Bloopers]
♫ 지난밤 내 꿈속엔 네가 왜 있고 ♫
♬  It just keeps looking like a coincidence  ♬
♫ 우연처럼 자꾸만 마주쳐 ♫
He's better.
-쟤가 나아? - 왼쪽에..
Cut it.
♫ 무심했던 말투도 ♫
Does he come out quietly?
♫ 점점 익숙해지고 ♫ 소리 안내고 나오나?
You said you heard me.
소리 난다며?
- I can't tell if you do that. - You're a goblin. You should know everything.
-그렇게 나오면 모르지! -뭐야 도깨비라면 다 알아야지!
♬  You, who I liked so much  ♬
♫  네가 좋아서가 아냐 Love  ♫
Cut. Please pull over to the right.
♫ 허전했던 마음이 요즘 들어 이상해 ♫ 오케이, 우측에 세워주세요.
♬  Love is so strange these days  ♬
♫ 요즘 들어 이상해 ♫
♬  Love is complicated by the moonlit night  ♬
♫ Love 달빛 내린 밤도  ♫
Did you do this on purpose?
♫ You you you if you still awake ♫ 일부러 이랬냐 너?
I thought you'd leave me at the buckwheat field, but you brought...
♫ 어떤 생각하는지  ♫ 메밀밭에다 버리고 올 줄 알았는데, 데리고 오는..
♬  You You You. If you feel alone  ♬
♫ You you you if you feel alone  ♫
♬  I feel the same as you  ♬
♫ 나와 똑같은 기분  ♫
♬  Sometimes I get awkward for no reason  ♬
♫ 가끔은 이유 없이 어색해지고 ♫ 아
I'm sorry.
♫ 가끔은 이유 없이 어색해지고 ♫ 죄송합니다.
Could the Uncle down the hall be the reincarnation of your sister, Uncle?
♫ 바보 같은 말들만 늘어놔 ♫ 끝방 삼촌이 삼촌 여동생의 환생아니야?
Say, "Orebeoni," Uncle down the hall.
♫ 바보 같은 말들만 늘어놔 ♫ 오라버니 한 번 해봐요 끝방 삼촌.
You wanna die?
-죽는다?
♬ Countless stars look beautiful  ♬
♫ 셀 수 없는 별들도 아름다워 보이죠 ♫
You think I'm happy?
나는 좋은 줄 알어?!
Jinx.
쳐다보지 마.
♬  It feels like you’re shaking  ♬
♫ 떨리는 듯한 ♫